<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?asciidoc-toc?>
<?asciidoc-numbered?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xl="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:lang="en">
<info>
<title>Liam Bennett</title>
</info>
<section xml:id="_employment_details">
<title>Employment Details</title>
<section xml:id="_july_2016_present_claranet_limited_london">
<title>July 2016 - Present: Claranet Limited (London)</title>
<simpara>:: <emphasis>Head of Portfolio Architecture and Engineering</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara>As Head of Portfolio Architecture I am responsible for the architecture and tooling underpinning all of Claranet UK&#8217;s portfolio of services. This includes supporting the definition of services, working with vendors and managing budgets for the investment in tools and in-house engineering capability.</simpara>
<simpara>In addition, this role comes with the responsibility for the software development teams building internal tools for engineers in addition to customer facing tools and services. Focused on scaling these teams, evolving agile software development practices and delivering customer products based on flow and empathy.</simpara>
<simpara>:: <emphasis>Cloud Practice Director</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara>As the Cloud Practice Director, I was responsible for the entire cloud engineering team of 40+ engineers across all supported cloud platforms (Azure, AWS, GCP, VMware) as well as Cloud Economists and Learning and Development.</simpara>
<simpara>My focus has been to grow the Cloud team whilst creating and evolving a culture that is aligned to the purpose, values and goals for the business.</simpara>
<simpara>:: <emphasis>Technical Principal (CloudOps)</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara>This was a combined management and delivery role. I managed the initial team of 8 engineers, as the Technical Principal. I was much more engaged across the multi-cloud portfolio (Azure, AWS and GCP) supporting the expansion and definition of new service offerings to customers.</simpara>
<simpara>:: <emphasis>Azure Practice Lead</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara>With a Windows team already established I took on a new role to build and grow the team and capability with Microsoft Azure.
This was a very entrepreneurial/leadership role within the business where I was leading all elements of the business growth including hiring the team, partner management with Microsoft and pre-sales with C-level customer prospects.</simpara>
<simpara>:: <emphasis>Windows Cloud Practice Lead - Bashton Ltd</emphasis></simpara>
<simpara>I joined Claranet just 6 months after the acquisition of Bashton Ltd - their first acquisition for public cloud capability. The initial expectation of this role was to build a team to support the deployment and on-going support of Windows infrastructure and applications on AWS.</simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="_feb_2014_july_2016_opentable_international_limited_london">
<title>Feb 2014 - July 2016: OpenTable International Limited (London)</title>
<simpara>:: <emphasis>Senior Infrastructure Engineer</emphasis></simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="_june_2010_feb_2014_mimecast_ltd_london">
<title>June 2010 - Feb 2014: Mimecast Ltd (London)</title>
<simpara>:: <emphasis>DevTools Engineer</emphasis></simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="_feb_2009_june_2010_saga_holidays_ltd_folkestone_kent">
<title>Feb 2009 - June 2010: Saga Holidays Ltd (Folkestone, Kent)</title>
<simpara>:: <emphasis>System Consultant (Java Developer)</emphasis></simpara>
</section>
<section xml:id="_sept_2006_aug_2007_nexor_ltd_nottingham">
<title>Sept 2006 - Aug 2007: Nexor Ltd (Nottingham)</title>
<simpara>:: <emphasis>Placement Student</emphasis></simpara>
</section>
</section>
<section xml:id="_education">
<title>Education</title>
<itemizedlist>
<listitem>
<simpara>University of Kent at Canterbury - Bsc Computer Science with Year in the Industry</simpara>
</listitem>
<listitem>
<simpara>Norton Knatchbull Secondary School</simpara>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</section>
</article>